<PRESDOCU>
            <PROCLA>
                <PRTPAGE P="26891"/>
                <PROC>Proclamation 11028 of May 7, 2026</PROC>
                <HD SOURCE="HED">Victory Day for World War II, 2026</HD>
                <PRES>By the President of the United States of America</PRES>
                <PROC>A Proclamation</PROC>
                <FP>As we celebrate Victory Day for World War II -- we celebrate America's monumental triumph over tyranny and evil in Europe, led by the might of our Armed Forces and those of our Allies. On May 8, 1945, the iron grip of Nazi Germany shattered, and news of victory swept across our great Nation and the world, marking a decisive turning point in the history of freedom.</FP>
                <FP>From the legendary storming of the beaches of Normandy to the frigid, hard-fought defense during the Battle of the Bulge, the courage of countless American soldiers carried the Allied cause across the deserts of North Africa and the forests of western Europe until the forces of the Nazi regime collapsed in ruin. Their sacrifice, together with the unwavering resolve of millions of men and women on the home front, drove tyranny to its knees and paved the way for the Allied powers to secure their resounding victory against Imperial Japan nearly 4 months later.</FP>
                <FP>The fight for liberty came at a staggering cost. More than 250,000 Americans laid down their lives in the fight against the Nazi regime. Their heroic sacrifice reminds us that the sacred freedoms we cherish are forged in sacrifice and must be fiercely defended both at home and abroad. Let us remember them, and the millions of innocent souls who endured horrendous atrocities, and lost their lives, at the hands of national socialism.</FP>
                <FP>As we celebrate 250 years of American independence, we carry their legacy forward by ensuring our Armed Forces remain the most dominant in the world, ready to safeguard our sovereignty, to confront any threat, and preserve the flame of liberty they fought so valiantly to defend.</FP>
                <FP>NOW, THEREFORE, I, DONALD J. TRUMP, President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim May 8, 2026, as a day in celebration of Victory Day for World War II.</FP>
                <PRTPAGE P="26892"/>
                <FP>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this seventh day of May, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-six, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and fiftieth.</FP>
                <GPH SPAN="1" DEEP="80" HTYPE="RIGHT">
                    <GID>Trump.EPS</GID>
                </GPH>
                <PSIG> </PSIG>
                <FRDOC>[FR Doc. 2026-09506 </FRDOC>
                <FILED>Filed 5-11-26; 11:15 am]</FILED>
                <BILCOD>Billing code 3395-F4-P</BILCOD>
            </PROCLA>
        </PRESDOCU>